功 夫
By aBU 20170207
INSPECTOR CHAN
SUPER CRIME FIGHTERS
还有谁？
Anyone else?
这么漂亮的一个女人
Such a beautiful woman...
就因为往地上吐了一口口水
...and you arrest her...
就被你们给抓到这儿来
...just for spitting?
还有王法吗？
Is there no justice?
还有法律吗？
Is there no law?
你们局长都得给我们鳄鱼帮面子
Commissioner is only your boss...
要不然他就当不了这个局长
...because he paid his dues to the Crocodile Gang.
你他妈的不认识我？
And you don't fucking know me?
对不起，我真的不知道她是你的太太
Sorry, I didn't know she was your wife.
你还敢躲！
Ugly coward!
走！
Go
看什么看？没见过这么帅的老大？
What are you looking at? Never seen such a handsome gang boss?
我做什么生意都不会做电影
Who'd be in the film business?
星期天电影院一个人都没有
It's Sunday, and the theater's deserted.
车子呢？
Where's the car?
回去！
Let's go back inside!
叫人！
Call for help!
不用发了，乡巴老
No need for that, Northerner.
你打警察的时候
While you were messing with the cop,
你的小弟已经全都被我搞定了
your men signed up with us.
斧头帮，我跟你拼了
I'll kill all you Axe Gangsters!
慢着！慢着！
Stop!
你还记得吗？我还请你吃过饭呢
You forget the time I treated you to dinner.
琛哥
Brother Sum.
大哥，你放过我吧
Please... Please spare me.
别傻了，大嫂
Don't worry.
我不杀女人，你走吧
I don't kill women. You can go!
谢谢大哥
Thank you, Big Brother.
警察出来洗地了
Cops! Come clean up the mess!
斧头帮
THE AXE GANG
这是一个社会动荡，黑帮横行的年代， 其中又以“斧头帮”最令人闻风丧胆。
In a time of social unrest and disorder.
the gangs have moved in to consolidate their power.
The most feared of them all is the Axe Gang.
唯独一些连黑帮也没兴趣的贫困社区， 却可享有暂时的安宁。
Only in the poorest districts, which hold no interest for the gangs...
can people live in peace.
PIG STY ALLE Y
1，2，3
One, two, three!
苦力强，行不行啊？
- That okay, Coolie?
行！
- No problem!
TAILOR
NOODLES AND CONGEE
阿鬼，算帐
My check, please, Donut.
唉
Yi!
多少钱？
- How much?
送的，送的！
- It's on the house!
你可真懂事啊
Donut.
谢了
Thank
小意思，小意思
- It's nothing. - I like you.
我回去了，跟老婆商量一下
I'll ask the wife about
减你的租金
lowering your rent.
多谢了
Thankyou!
包租公，早
Morning, Landlord!
包租公！早
Landlord!
小朱，又长高了
Jill! How you've grown!
来，过来，叔叔给你检查身体
Come let me examine you!
包租公，这么巧啊
Good to see you, Landlord!
巧什么巧啊
What's so good about it?
别这样…！
Don't...!
胜哥，这件衣服的叉我想开高点了
Can you make the skirt slit higher?
没问题！
Sure!
哎呀，有流星啊！
Look, a comet!
阿珍！你来真的？
Jane! You naughty girl!
哎呀包租公，你怎么这样啊？
Landlord! You're such a scoundrel!
阿珍…你别走啊，阿珍
Don't go, Jane! Stay and chat!
再聊一会儿，来，别走啊你
I'm only kidding.
阿珍
Jane!
包租婆
Landlady!
包租婆！
为什么突然之间没水了呢？
What happened to the water?
水费不用花钱哪？你们这些混蛋
Water ain't free!
这个月房租也不交
You talk a lot for someone
还那么多废话说
who won't pay his rent.
但是我的头洗到一半，你把水闸关了
But I'm in the middle of a shampoo.
我不光是现在关
You think that's a problem?
从明天开始，逢一、三、五停水
From now on, no water on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays.
二、四、六间歇性供水，怎样？
Water ration Tuesdays, Thursdays and Saturdays.
斜眉歪眼，一个个鬼哭狼嚎什么？
I just love hearing
找死啊？
you fools complain.
我看你们都活腻了！
Assholes!
Goodmorning,包租婆！
Good morning, Landlady!
果你妈个头啊！
Assholes!
你今天要是再不交租的话
Just pay your rent,
我就烧了你铺子
or I'll burn your shop down.
笑，笑什么啊？
What's so funny?
笑就不用交租了，老屁眼
Rent's no laughing matter, fairy!
这么有力气，活该你一辈子做苦力
Serves you right you're a coolie!
欠我几个月租金
Months overdue and
早上连招呼也不打一声
not even a "good morning."
累死你个王八蛋！
You'll be a coolie for life.
别以为你长得帅我就不打你
There you go, handsome!
喂，怎么买粥买那么久啊？
What took you so long with the congee?
这不是买回来了吗
I stopped to
我刚才帮忙扶个老婆婆过马路嘛
help an old lady cross the street.
那你在这干嘛？
- What are you doing here?
我看看有没有色鬼偷看人洗澡
- Checking for Peeping Toms.
六婶，有没有色鬼偷看你洗澡？
Was someone just spying on you, Auntie Six?
六婶，无凭无据，你别乱指啊你
Don't shoot your mouth off without proof.
神经病，无凭无据
She's crazy.
别闹了！
Go away!
叔叔，可不可以教我们踢球啊？
Please can you teach us, sir?
还踢球！
No more soccer!
哪位剪头？
- Who wants the cut?
我大哥
- My boss.
请坐
Take a seat.
剪完！谢谢，五毛钱
Done! Fifty cents, please.
哇
Wo
很漂亮吧？
Isn't it great?
干嘛剪那么漂亮？
It's too good!
谁叫你剪那么漂亮的？
Why'd you make him look so good?
找茬啊？
Why?
大哥，你别生气
Don't get mad, boss.
他是我朋友，让我来跟他说
He's my old buddy. I'll handle this.
斧头帮大哥，两把斧头你也亲眼看到了
He's boss of the Axe Gang. Don't you see the two axes?
坏人哪
We're bad guys.
你把他头剪那么漂亮，要死人的，知道吗？
Making him look good is really bad. Understand?
不知道
- I didn't know.
哎呀，所以说，你真是的！
- You're a numskull!
那跟你聊得很投缘，你赔点医药费
But I like you, so just pay me,
我帮你摆平，好不好？
and I'll take care of it.
不好！
No way!
大哥，不要拿斧头啊你，收起来先
Steady with the axe, boss.
我再跟他说
Let me talk to him.
这次帮你出头，你亲眼看见的
I really care for you. You saw it for yourself.
我没骗你啊
Seriously.
你方不方便，多少拿点出来
Why don't you pay up. Not much.
摆个十桌八桌，要不半桌也行
Enough for a drink.
哦，原来你勒索我
Oh, so it's blackmail!
大哥
Boss!
大哥！
大哥
Boss!
你死定了，我大哥一睡醒就砍人
Now you're dead!
哇，你看他就要醒了，马上
Looks like he's waking up!
我不怕
I'm not afraid.
就算杀了一个我，还有千千万万个我
You can kill me. But there'll be thousands more of me!
出头鸟啊？斧头帮大哥在里面睡午觉
You want to play tough? The Axe Gang boss is napping in there.
哪个不怕死的，向前一步啊
Whoever wants to die, step forward.
哦，那就是没的商量
So you want to fight?
好啊，江湖规矩，单挑啊
Great! We'll go one-on-one.
就是一个对一个，谁也不想犯规啊
Don't even think about cheating.
拿葱的那个大婶，出来！
That old woman with the onion!
表情那么凶干什么啊？
You look real tough.
以为打得赢我啊你？
Want to try me?
我让你一拳都可以，打我啊
I'll let you hit me first.
大婶，干什么的你？
What do you do?
俺是耕田的
I'm a farmer.
耕田就好好耕田吧你，滚回田里去吧
Farmers don't fight. Piss off!
有毛病！
He's crazy!
做错事还顶嘴啊你！
Calling me names?
不是看你有毛病，我早K你了
You're lucky you're a woman.
那个矮子！五尺差半寸那个，就是你
Hey, shorty! Yeah, you!
矮要承认，挨打站稳，出来啊
If you're short, you don't retort.
这辈子我最看不起那些不老实的人了
What did I say about cheating?
坐下！
Sit back down!
戴眼镜那老伯那么拽，出来
You! The geezer with the glasses. You look mean.
我不是叫你啊老伯，我叫那个…
No, not you. I mean...
那个小鬼！
You!
小鬼，我忍你很久了，出来
Hey, kid, let's rumble!
行了…够大了，够大了
All right, all right!
哎，没有一个像人的
So no one-on-ones today.
是你们自己不争气的噢
You're all such wimps!
今天的决斗取消了
他勒索我
He blackmailed me.
哦，肥婆，负责人就是你，是吧？
Fat woman, you're in charge here, right?
肥婆了！
Fat woman, my ass!
唉，斧头帮啊！
I'm with the Axe Gang!
斧头帮了！
Axe Gang, my ass!
大哥！
Boss!
大哥了！
Boss, my ass!
赔汤药费啊你！
- You have to pay our medical bills!
汤药费了！
- Bills, my ass!
自己人！
- We're on the same side!
自己人了你！
- Same side,
好了
Ok
我靠，靠
my ass!
有种啊你！我叫人！
Think you're so tough? I'll call for backup!
腰里揣着死耗子，冒充打猎的
You nitwit!
我看你叫谁！
Let's see you call backup!
一枝穿云箭，千军万马来相见
You don't know the backup I have. I'm talking an army here.
等死吧你，你别走啊！你啊
Don't you go away!
买棺材吧你
Go put a down payment on your coffin!
谁扔的炮仗？
Who threw the firecracker?
自己人，大哥
I'm one of you, brother.
你们这么多事干什么啊？
Mind your own business!
下雨了，赶快回家收衣服
It's raining. Go bring in your laundry!
肥婆！
Fat woman!
你也想勒索我？
You blackmailing me too?
我不怕
I ain't afraid.
啊？
Ah!
我…
I...
怎么会这样？有没有看见？
Did anyone see what happened?
别动！断了！
Don't! My back's broken!
叫人…叫人！
Call for help!
走！
Go
大哥，你别生气
Hold on, calm down.
你吃了东西没有？我这里…
You hungry?
老实点！
Keep quiet.
不要！
No.
是谁干的？
Who did this?
我数三下
I'll count to three.
１…
One...
２…
...two...
是我做的
I did it!
琛哥，这些货行不行？
Are the goods okay, Brother Sum?
对不起，琛哥
Sorry!
小孩子别看，转过去
Look away, kid.
扔出去
Get rid of him!
从来只有我们斧头帮欺负人
We're the bad guys!
没有人敢欺负我们
We're meant to do the ass-kicking...
今天我们伤了二十几个弟兄
...not the other way around.
就因为这两家伙，冒充我们斧头帮
And it's all because these morons posed as Axes.
琛哥…这个还用您操心吗？
Don't waste your time, Brother Sum.
您现在迷迷糊糊的，小心别摔着了
We'll handle this.
那个谁，搞定他
You! Take care of it.
神偷啊，会开锁
- Boy, can this guy pick locks.
混口饭吃，给个机会
- It's a living. Give me a break.
好，有两下子，把那个也开了吧
Pick that one too, if you're so good.
来
Come.
我只数三声啊
I'll count to three.
快点
Hurry!
预备，３！
Ready? Three!
真有两下子！
That's quick!
琛哥
Brother Sum,
其实我们是很想加入斧头帮
we really want to be Axes.
所以才去冒充的
That's why we did what we did.
给个机会吧你，好不好？
Give us a chance.
你杀过人没有？
Ever killed anyone?
杀人这种事，我整天都有这种想法的
I've always thought about it.
先杀个人让我看看
Then go kill someone.
那我现在就去杀人了，好不好？
I will!
嗯
Em!
去吧！
Go on!
多谢琛哥！
Thank you, Brother Sum.
这种他妈的担色，总有一天用得着的
We can always find a use for that type.
我说过多少遍了跟你
I told you before,
要狠嘛
you've got to look tough.
狠一点！
Tougher!
再狠一点，样子！
要演就演全套吧你
Act the part.
不要每次都睡着了
And try to stay awake.
装狠很累的
It's tiring being tough.
累？糊口啊，大哥
Tiring? It's our living!
这个世界，满街都是钱，遍地都是女人
The streets out there are filled with money and women.
谁能够下决心就可以争的赢
You only need the will and determination...
谁能够把握机会就能出人头地
...to seize the opportunity to win.
现在机会来了
This is our big chance!
狠下心杀个人，正式加入斧头帮
We just kill someone, and we're in the gang.
那么钱和女人就全都有了
Then it'll be money and women all the way!
千万别像这些臭要饭的，你看你看
Don't be like those beggars...
没一个上进，混吃等死
...with no ambition.
看什么啊，四眼崽？
Who are you looking at, four-eyes?
再看打爆你的眼镜
I'll smash your glasses!
去死吧！要饭的
Get lost!
有种下车啊你！
Come here and say that!
你真要去杀人啊？
- You're really gonna kill someone?
那还用说！
- That's right!
我先杀光四眼崽
The four-eyes,
再杀城寨里那个肥婆还有那些王八蛋街坊
the fat woman and all the residents of Pig Sty.
那些王八蛋街坊武功很高的
But they're good at kung fu.
武功，我也会啊！
- I can do kung fu!
你也会？
- Oh, yeah?
难道我学过如来神掌也要说给你听吗？
Didn't I tell you I know Buddhist Palm kung fu?
唉，小弟，小弟，别走啊
Hey there, handsome boy. Stop.
哇，不得了，不得了啊
Amazing!
你有道灵光从天灵盖喷出来，你知道吗？
Do you know you have a special aura?
年纪轻轻的就有一身横练的筋骨
You're so young, but you have the bone structure...
简直百年一见的练武奇材啊
and chi flow of a kung-fu genius.
如果有一天，让你打通任督二脉
If your chi flow can be channeled,
那还不飞龙上天哪
then you will be invincible!
正所谓：我不入地狱，谁入地狱
Like the old saying: You cannot escape your destiny.
警恶惩奸，维护世界和平这个任务
The duty of upholding world peace
就交给你了，好吗？
and punishing evil will be yours.
唔
Sure.
这本《如来神掌秘笈》是无价之宝
This is the scroll of the Buddhist Palm. It's priceless.
我看与你有缘，收你十块钱，传授给你吧
But as it's fate, I'll let you have it for $ 10.
BUDDHIST PALM MANUAL
你把全部家当都给他了？
- You gave him your life savings? - Yes.
是，本来打算用这笔钱去读书
I was saving to study
将来可以做个医生或者律师
to be a doctor or lawyer...
但是为了维护世界和平
...but this was world peace.
放开那女孩！
Let go of the girl!
哇，如来神掌啊
Hey! It's the Buddhist Palm!
还卖两分钱一本
"The 20-Cent Kung Fu Manual."
真有钱啊
You must be loaded.
想打死人啊？
Have you killed anyone lately?
一个傻子，一个哑巴，死一边去吧
He's a fool, and she's mute. Losers!
从此以后，我明白好人没好报
I realized then that good guys never win.
我要做坏人
I want to be bad.
我要杀人
I want to be the killer!
冰淇淋啊！
- Ice cream!
哪里？
- Where?
两杯，我要奶油的
Make mine a vanilla.
我要巧克力！
Chocolate for me!
看什么？没看过吃东西不给钱啊？
What're you looking at? Never seen free ice cream before?
追哦！
Look at her run!
你们三个家伙这么能打，外面有的是活干
You're such kung-fu masters,
去卖武啊！笨蛋
go take it on the road.
还装孙子，窝在这里干什么啊？
You belong in the circus, not here!
包租婆，别这么说
Don't say that, Landlady.
他们应该有苦衷的
There must be a reason they're here.
家家都有本难念的经
Everyone has his reasons.
其实我们也不想连累你
We don't want to make trouble.
你知道就好了，得罪了斧头帮
I'm glad you get it. The mob's mad at us.
我们还有好日子过吗？还不快点给我滚
We'll never hear the end of it. Why don't you get lost!
包租婆有点过份了
Your wife shouldn't be so nasty.
你还好吗？
You okay?
三位师父
Masters.
我家没有东西送给你们
We have nothing precious to give you...
这是一点点心意
...but take this as a token of our appreciation.
谢谢你救我们
Thanks for saving us!
等上坟的时候再哭吧，在这演戏
Stop the crying. This isn't a show!
你怎样这样铁石心肠
- You're so cold-hearted.
哟，还敢顶嘴？
- Talking back to me, eh?
你以为会点三脚猫功夫就不是兔子？
You may know kung fu, but you're still a fairy.
会功夫也不是罪啊
It's no crime to be good at kung fu!
你一天是兔子，就一辈子是兔子
Once a fairy, always a fairy.
你看你里边穿条红底裤，白里透红
Look at you. What's with the red underwear?
兜紧了没有？当心漏出来啊
Why not a diaper while you're at it.
穿红底裤也有罪吗？
What's wrong with red underwear?
你有事就躲起来，没事就赶人走
Where were you when there was trouble?
要不是他们三个，我们可就惨了
If it weren't for them, we'd be finished.
你做人讲不讲道理，啊？
Be reasonable!
好！我就跟你们讲道理
I'll reason with you.
你们三个家伙欠我三个月房租
You owe me three months' rent.
三三得九，九十块，拿来
That's $90.
有钱给钱，没钱就收拾包袱，滚
Pay up or pack up!
不用怕，我帮他们给
Don't you worry. I'll pay it.
龅牙珍，你做出头鸟是吧？
Think you're a smartass, Rabbit-Tooth Jane?
我现在就做出头鸟了，行不行？
What's it to you, tub of lard?
肥婆！
Bitch!
八婆！
包租婆，你不要这么暴躁
Calm down, Landlady.
欠着我房租不交，都吃了熊心豹子胆了
This is your fault. Are you trying to kill us?
怎么可以这样呢
- You're right.
人家刚才救了你
How could you do that?
造反了！
Shut the hell up!
跟我比嗓门，找死啊
You think you can out-yell me?
那肥婆像杀猪一样鬼叫，死有余辜
The fat lady can really sing.
学着点
Watch this!
为什么？
What happened?
什么为什么？
What do you mean, what happened?
你来扔
You try it.
我扔啊？
- Me?
快点！
- Quick!
不好意思，你觉得怎么样？
Sorry! You okay?
我觉得你可以往前一点，再瞄准一点
I think you should get closer and take better aim.
好不好？
Okay?
好！
Okay!
谁扔的刀把？
- Who's throwing the handles?
刀把？
- Handle?
又多了一把，刀把呢？
Where's the third knife?
我怎么知道扔到哪去了你
God knows where it went.
难道是同一把？没理由啊
Could it be the same one? Can't be...
不要！
- Don't!
不好意思
- Sorry.
你是不是有话想说？
What are you trying to say?
是啊，我办点重要事情先，再联络
I just remembered I have something to do. See you!
糟，被发现了
Uh-oh. They've seen us!
不要过来啊
Stay back!
不用怕！蛇最喜欢听音乐
Don't panic! Snakes like music.
我一吹口哨，他就不会咬人了
If I whistle, they won't bite.
我不会再信你了
Please, no more bright ideas.
再信一次
Oh, what the hell!
又是你这个王八蛋
Not you again, asshole!
别看了别看了，大家都散开了，都回去吧
Get back
这个人什么都乱说的
to your business!
分头走！
Split up!
走？
Split?
在这干什么啊你？
What're you doing here?
找你咯，你不是受伤了吗？
Looking for you. Weren't you hurt?
我没事啊！
I'm fine!
你怎么每次受伤都会没事的？
How come you always recover so fast?
我不知道
I don't know.
你看哪位医生啊？
- Which hospital did you go to?
我也完全不记得了
- Don't remember.
也好
Maybe it's better that way.
记忆是痛苦的根源
Memories can be painful.
你能不记得，算是福气了
To forget may be a blessing!
听你这么说，感触良多
I never knew you were so deep.
问君能有几多愁
All the sadness one can bear...
恰似一江春水向东流
...down the river everywhere.
走开啊！
Hey, get out of the way!
让一让，拜托
Move!
打爆你的眼镜！
I'll slap you to kingdom come!
你看那两个四眼崽
Look at those four-eyes
清明还没到，就背着个棺材板到处走
carting around a coffin.
脑袋进水
What morons!
别说是我逼你们走啊，咱们照老规矩来
Don't blame me for making you leave.
让菩萨做决定
We'll let Buddha decide...
请各位乡亲父老作证
...whether you stay...
上签就留，下签就走
...or go.
HORRIFICALLY BAD FATE
两位请用茶
Have some tea.
这次有劳两位这么专业人士到这儿来
We're grateful for some professional help.
这个我们全都明白
We understand the problem.
洪家铁线拳
Twelve Kicks from the Tam School...
五郎八卦棍，十二路谭腿
...Iron Fist from the Hung School
全部在这里
and the Hexagon Staff...
是比较棘手
Those guys at Pig Sty are really good.
之前他们都是一流高手
Their warrior days are long over...
只因厌倦了武林争斗而退出江湖
...but they're still top fighters.
这份工作，对我们来说非常具有挑战性
This job is a great challenge for us.
这个就叫专业
Now, that's professionalism.
当然了，杀手排行榜第一位
Number One Killers. Expensive,
物超所值，贵点也值得
yes, but worth every penny!
错！第一位是终极杀人王
No! Number one is the Beast,
火云邪神
the world's top killer.
他太醉心于武功
He was so dedicated to kung fu,
以至于练功走火入魔
he went crazy.
听说，现在已经住进精神病医院了
I heard he's now in an asylum.
那排行榜第一位始终还是两位
So you're the top killers now.
严格来说我们只不过是卖唱的
Strictly speaking, we're just musicians.
一曲肝肠断
A song that wrenches the heart.
天涯何处觅知音？
where do I find a knowing ear?
喂，好诗啊！是不是？
Great poem, isn't it?
一会儿就要分手了
We'll be saying goodbye soon.
不知道以后有没有机会再见面
Who knows when we'll see each other again.
原来大家都是同道中人
We're three of a kind.
早知道，就不会这么寂寞了
Wish we'd known before.
不如趁这个最后机会
Let's take this
我们来切磋一下
opportunity to spar a little.
别逗了，还有很多行李没收拾呢
No. We still have a lot to pack.
我也是说说而已
You're right.
对
right.
十二路谭腿攻守并重，名不虚传
Twelve Kicks of the Tam School! Superb attack and defense!
铁线拳刚中有柔，可谓拳中之尊！
Iron Fist: powerful yet delicate. Topnotch!
五郎八卦棍，千变万化，高深莫测！
Hexagon Staff, with its thousand moves. Mystical!
后会有期
Till we meet again!
又有口红
More lipstick!
炒菜咧，火一定要这样
Like this
这样，炒菜一定要大，知道吗？
Do you know?
你给我站住，再跑，再跑，我打死你
Stay there, or I'll break you in half.
不好意思，今天不做生意了
Sorry, we're closed.
做件衣服很快的
You can make a suit in no time.
我们要搬家了
We're moving.
这块布料是上品的
This is good material!
你挺识货的
You know your stuff.
这块布料的艺术成分很高
This has high artistic value.
有多高？
How high?
三、四楼那么高了
At least a few stories...
得罪斧头帮就是嫌命长
Insulting the Axe Gang! We'll show them.
先打死这三个王八蛋
Let's kill them all
再拿他们这去做烟花巷
and make this place a brothel.
叫你别挡着我！
Don't block my view!
什么事？
What's going on?
好！
Good!
叫你别挡着我
Don't block my view!
要命啊，叫那三个家伙赶快走
Damn! I told those nitwits to leave,
又打到这儿来了
but they're still here.
不是吧？
- Really?
是啊
- Yeah.
有没有搞错，在这里打架？
What the hell is this fighting?
打烂了东西谁赔？
Who'll pay for the damage?
对不起…没事没事
Sorry, sorry. It's nothing!
你们吵够了没啊！
You know what time it is?
现在几点了？不用睡觉了？！
I have to sleep.
死肥婆，你歇者吧你
Hey, fatso, eat shit and die!
我哪里说的不对了？你们吵的没完没了
Die? In this racket?
对不起…没事没事
Sorry, sorry!
别再挡了我看戏啊
Get out of my way!
撑住！
Hang in there, Tailor.
别再吵了！
Be quiet!
给条活路走行不行？不要赶尽杀绝
Give us a break! Why push us so far?
还有高手？
There's another master?
这就是狮吼功吗!
It's the Lion's Roar!
谁人打的太极拳？
I thought that was a myth.
狮吼功？太极拳？
Who knew the Lion's Roar really exists?
治好了也浪费汤药!算了！
That's the last we'll see of them.
不好了,琛哥！快开车!
It's bad, Brother Sum. Quick, start the car!
开车啊!
Start the car!
大哥!
Boss!
大什么哥!你有没有公德心呀？
Keep it down! Have you no manners?
又吵又闹的,街坊们不用睡觉了？
Get lost. People are trying to sleep.
人家明天还要上班耶！滚开!
They have to work tomorrow. Get out of here!
你们这些败类!
Scumbags!
没用的,我活不了多久了！
I can't hang on much longer.
能见到你们这些真正的高手
But having seen real masters like you...
我也不枉此生了
...I can now die in peace.
别这么说了,阿鬼
Don't say that.
我们只是想安享晚年的小市民
We're ordinary folks.
平凡是福
Ordinary's a blessing.
“高手”两个名，实在不想再背负了！
Don't call us masters.
你们两个这么厉害!
But you're such great fighters!
早点出手的话
If only you'd helped earlier,
他们就不会死得这么惨了
they wouldn't have to die this way.
就像阿鬼说的：家家有本难念的经
Like Donut said, everyone has his reasons.
当年为了比武,亲眼看到自已儿子被人打死
Years ago. we saw our only son killed in a fight.
冤冤相报何时了！望各位体谅!
Revenge can be devastating. Do you understand?
既然这样,你们把功夫传给我…
Why don't you train us to be top fighters...
让我成为绝世高手，为他们报仇!
...and we'll avenge them!
要成为绝世高手,并非一朝一夕
Becoming a top fighter takes time.
除非是天生武学奇才
Unless you're a natural-born kung-fu genius.
但是这种人…是万中无一呀！
And they're one in a million.
很明显,我就是这种人!
It's obvious I'm the one!
看来,他不是
Don't think so.
各位!我夫妻俩曾经发过毒誓,不再显露武功
Everyone! We swore we'd never fight again.
但今天不出手也出手了
But we broke that promise today.
为了安全,我们尽快离开这里吧!
For your own safety, please all leave!
能力越大,责任就越大
In great power lies great responsibility.
你避不了的！
There's no escaping from it.
阿鬼,你伤得这么重！不要动气呀
Donut, you're hurt bad. Rest now.
阿鬼,你还是说中文吧
We can't understand what you're saying.
阿鬼!
Donut!
四眼仔！我认得你!
I know you, four-eyes!
看来，这位先生对戴眼镜人士,有很深的成见
You seem prejudiced against the sight-challenged.
没错,尤其是金丝眼镜
That's right. Especially gold-framed four-eyes.
我身为文员,戴金丝眼镜是很合理,也很合逻辑的
Gold frames are perfect for clerks.
我戴得好看，为什么你一定要针对我？
I think I look good. So why keep picking on me?
帮忙!
Help me!
帮忙是吧？……地痞是吧？
"Help me! Help me!" Want to play, punks?
龙形是吧？虎形是吧？
The Dragon Style? The Tiger Style?
你下车…
Come down here,
我就打暴你的眼镜,下车!
and I'll smash your glasses. Come on!
你信不信我打暴他眼镜？
You know I'd do it, right?
你发誓!
Swear to it!
发誓啊!
Swear!
你看不起我啊？
Have you no respect?
刚才叫你帮忙,你在干嘛？
Where were you when I needed you?
汪什么啊!
You sound like a wimp!
这么嚣张,你挨打真是活该
We always get beat!
这么久以来,杀人放火打劫强奸非礼…
We haven't gotten anywhere.
没有一次能做到…
No killing, no arson, no robberies, no rapes..
就是因为你这头肥猪碍手碍脚!
...all because of you!
教而不善,烂泥扶不上墙!
You're a numb-nut!
跟我来!
Follow me!
打劫,钱放在哪？
It's a stickup! Where's the money?
放在哪？说吧
Where's the money?
看什么看？看不起我啊!
What're you looking at? I'm serious!
我杀人不眨眼!钱放哪？
I kill people for less! Give me the money.
说!
Talk to me
钱在这里
The money's in here.
放开那个女孩!
Let go of the girl!
一个傻子,一个哑巴
He's a fool, and she's mute.
死一边去吧!
Losers!
别再跟着我!我迟早被你连累死!
Go away! You're dragging me down!
就说你是烂泥扶不上墙
Go home and raise pigs.
回家养猪去吧
打死你!
Go, before I kill you.
那个谁!那个谁谁谁!
You! Whatsyourname!
来,拿去添行头！从今天起,你就是斧头帮的了!
Take this and get some new clothes. You're now an Axe!
不会吧？
- For real?
没错!有个老朋友等着你呢
- Someone's waiting for you.
-琛哥! -我一看你的样子…
Brother Sum! One look at you,
就知道你除了好事,什么都敢做
and I knew you'd do anything.
-是呀! -你只欠一个机会
Right! You just needed your chance.
-是呀! -有件事要你帮忙
Damn right! We've an assignment for you.
赴汤蹈火,琛哥!
Anything, Brother Sum!
“不正常人类研究中心”
"Research on abnormal people."
-这是什么呀？ -精神病院
What's that? A mental asylum.
报告长官!
Sir
-有军队! -那些是童子军!
Soldiers! Boy Scouts!
-还有坦克! -关你屁事！镇静点！
Tanks! No worries.
趁童子军换班的时候，你有五分钟的时间
When the Boy Scouts change shifts, you have exactly five minutes.
跟着地图指示的箭头
Follow the arrows on the map.
到地下室最后那个房间
Go to the last cell...
打开门锁,把里面那个人带出来！就这么简单！
...and get the man inside there out.
家伙都在这儿！走！
Here's your tools.
-那你们呢？ -我们帮你把风啊
What about you guys? We're your lookouts.
只有五分钟,快点吧!
Five minutes. Hurry!
终极第一杀人王火云邪神…
The world's top killer indeed
果然有派头!
looks the part!
虚名而已
It's only a title.
废话少说,我们想请你帮忙杀两个人
Cut the bullshit. We want two people killed.
开个价吧！
Name your price.
开什么价？
Name my what?
我是杀了很多人，就是想找个能打赢我的人
I've killed so many trying to find a worthy adversary.
最后发现，没人是我的对手才躲起来清静一下！
So far, I've never found one.
如果有对手的话，我早就出来了！
That's why I stayed inside. Had I met my match,
哪有人困得住我呀？
I'd have been out long ago.
告诉你如果有绝世高手，我免费见一个杀一个!
If you find me a worthy opponent. I'll do it for free. No charge!
有没有呀？
Do you have someone?
是真正的绝世高手啊！
Yes.
正合你的胃口呀,邪神先生
Brilliant fighters who are up to the challenge.
不过不知道你介不介意先露两手呢？
But first, will you show us some moves?
不是不相信你，我们大家想开开眼界
Not that we don't trust you. We want to see you in action.
你们这些废物,根本没资格要我出手!
You numskulls aren't worthy!
琛哥！
Sam!
真的假的？
He doesn't look the part.
内衣裤拖鞋是挻标奇立异的
The slippers are a little crappy.
如果帮他整理一下，他应该会有前途的
But he'll clean up well.
-去你妈的,是不是救错人了？ -绝对没有
You sure you got the right guy? Absolutely.
我发誓,绝对是照着吩咐去做的
I swear I did exactly what you told me.
火云邪神,你耍两招让大家开开眼界，不要让我难做!
Please show us some moves, Mr. Beast. Don't make it hard for me!
神经病!
You dumb or what?
老伯,这是什么？
You know what this is, old man?
沙包一样大的拳头你见过没有？
Ever seen a fist this big?
不要逼我出手！我发起疯来,连自已也怕呀!
Don't force me to fight. I scare myself when I fight!
是吗？出手吧
Really? Try me, then.
怎么样？他没事吧？
Is he okay?
老头,你很能打是吗？
So you say you can fight?
用力!
Harder!
用力啊!
打人都没力气，还说是黑社会？
You hit like that and call yourself a gangster?
咦,洋枪!
A foreign gun!
天下武功，无坚不破，唯快不破
In the world of kung fu, speed defines the winner.
火云邪神武功盖世
The Beast is the best of them all.
斧头帮全体同仁向邪神敬礼!
The Axe Gang extends its respect!
绝世高手就在这里!
The real masters, together in one room!
看来,只有当年终极杀人王火云邪神…
Only the world's top killer...
才有这样的煞气
...has such an aura.
这种气势…
Likewise.
难道就是人称神雕侠侣的…？
Could you two be the fated lovers...?
-杨过-小龙女!
Paris... and Helen of Troy!
久仰大名
A pleasure, indeed.
今天我们是来和斧头帮算帐的，与其他人无关
We're here to deal with the Axe Gang and only the Axe Gang.
你当初杀了，我不就什么事都没了？
You should've killed me before.
今天才来算帐,那不是自投罗网？
Now you're committing suicide.
留你狗命多活两天,别那么嚣张
You're living on borrowed time.
我这份大礼,你今天收定了!
You can't escape your fate!
送钟？
What's this? A funeral bell?
今天有邪神在这儿，看是谁给谁送终!
With the Beast here, let's see whose funeral it is!
你做出头鸟是吧？
So you're on their side?
不要误会
Don't get me wrong.
我只是想打死两位，或者被两位打死
I only want to kill you or be killed by you.
老婆,你怎么看？
What do you think?
自古正邪不两立…
The good cannot coexist with the bad.
我不入地狱,谁入地狱？
You can't escape your destiny.
既然是这样,来吧
So be it. Let's do it.
好啊
Okay.
来吧!
Let's do it!
用点力,我还行！
Piece of cake. I can handle this.
力度够了,不过准确度差点
Good try, but a little off target.
狮吼功？
The Lion's Roar?
等等!
Wait!
想不到狮吼功还有一招大喇叭!
I didn't know the Lion's Roar could be done with a speaker!
小弟甘拜下风!
What a blow!
他们好像动不了!
- Looks like they're not up to it!
绝对是!趁他虚要他命!
- Let's get them while they're down.
你来!
You do it!
-我想吐…我要去看医生! -你去吃屎吧!
- I'm gonna puke! I need to see a doctor! - Go to hell!
你!过来!
You! Come over here.
-打他!-好!
- Hit him! - Yes!
-打头!-当然了!
- The head! - Of course!
-照头打下去!-好!
- Hit him on the head! - Okay.
-扬名立万!-来啦!
- Here's your chance. - Got it!
-打他!-打他呀!
- Hit him! - Hit him!
-打他妈的!-打啦!
- Hit the shit out of him! - Right!
-打呀!-打他呀!
- Hit him! - Hit him!
打他妈的!
Beat the shit out of him!
你干什么？
What're you doing?
你到底想我打他本人还是打他的妈啊？
You want me to hit him or beat the shit out of him?
你搞得我好乱啊!
You're making me very confused!
沙包这么大的拳头,怎么练的？
Wow, that's a big fist!
为什么要打我？
Why did you hit me?
人呢？去哪儿了？
Where are they?
有没有搞错！居然让他们跑了？
How could you let them escape?
没人可以在我手上跑掉的!
No one gets away from me!
为什么是他救了我们？
Why did he save us?
年轻人,行差踏错一定会了
Young people make mistakes.
能悬崖勒马,还有得救！
But at least he finally made good.
你看他!被人打得他老妈都不认得了！
Look at him! Beaten to a pulp.
你还有什么心愿？你说吧
Do you have any last requests?
喂!大哥!
Hey, wait!
你还是写中文吧？
Why don't you write in Chinese?
不懂啊,喂!
I don't understand.
哎！没有啊!
There's no one here!
CHINESE MEDICINE
能够撑到现在,简直就是奇迹
It's a miracle he lasted this long.
是我们的药神奇吧？
The herbs should help him.
药只不过是辅助
Herbal medicine can only partly help.
关键是他本身的体质
The key is his own body structure.
全身骨折,经脉尽断，不仅没有死…
All his bones and tendons are broken.
还在这么短时间自动复原
It's amazing he's recovering so fast.
平常人根本就不可能…
It can't be possible...
除非他是…
Unless he's...
什么味道？
What's that smell?
受伤就不要抽烟了
You mustn't smoke while you're hurt.
这里交给我吧
Let me handle this.
不可能的
This makes no sense.
想不到火云邪神间接打通了他的任督二脉…
Who knew the Beast could clear the chi flow...
将他的潜能逼了出来
...and thus unleash the boy's true potential?
其实,我们早就应该想到
We should've guessed.
他就是万中无一的绝世高手!
He is the one!
有这样的事？
Is this for real?
好哇！原来你这个叛徒还没死？
You're still alive, you turncoat?
兄弟们,砍死他!
Kill him, men!
踩脚指头？
What kind of move is that?
小孩打架才出这招!
Kids' stuff!
如果我们儿子没死，也该有他这么大了
If our son were alive, he'd be his age now.
如果他能好好读书，我看他将来不是医生就是律师
If he studies hard, he could grow up to be a doctor or lawyer.
不过看他的样子应该当武师!
A stuntman, more likely!
不错,来呀！
Not bad. Let's go.
子弹我也抓得住…
I can even stop bullets...
-居然是昆仑派的蛤蟆功？ -这下糟了!
What? The Toad Style of the Kwan Lun School? Oh, no!
老公,你记不记得有一招从天而降的掌法？
Remember the Palm move that falls from heaven?
是已经失传了的如来神掌
That's the long lost Buddhist Palm.
投降啦!
I surrender!
你这是什么掌法？
What kind of move was that?
你想学啊？我教你
If you want to learn, I'll teach you.
我输了!
Master!
这两个你认不认得啊？叫他们别把鼻涕抹在玻璃上
Hey! Tell him not to put snot on the glass.
你们两个把裤子穿上啊!
You two, put your pants on!
你们是不是要买？不买不要舔呀!
No licking if you're not buying!
小弟,看你的骨格精奇…
Kid, you have the bone structure
是万中无一的练武奇材
of a kung-fu genius.
维护世界和平就靠你了
World peace is in your hands.
我这里有本秘笈
Here's the scroll of the Buddhist Palm.
我看与你有缘,就十块钱卖给你吧！等等!
Because it's fate, I'll let you have it for $ 10. Wait!
这本书不适合啊？还有
You want more...?